I'm a full stack software engineer specializing in both server-side and client-side JavaScript and the .NET framework. With over 7 years of professional experience, I have had the opportunity to contribute to an array of projects that run the gambit from federal government intranets and tools, to private business enterprise web applications, to building websites for digital marketing agencies, to working entrepreneurially as a freelance consultant. I have had to become adaptable to work on teams both small and large and have owned significant portions of code and team processes that have directly impacted the organizations' growth as well as the internal team efficiencies.

EXPERIENCE

Charter Communications Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2021 - Present • Denver, CO

• Providing technical insight and engineering support on the core design systems team. We author and make design decisions that impact the entire suite of Spectrum products at Charter, and I build the tech around it. Currently, I'm building out our new technical documentation site in TypeScript and Vue 3. I also optimize the web performance and accessibility of our design system components and help shape the developer experience for all product engineers utilizing our components across React, Angular, Vue, and vanilla JavaScript component libraries.

Architect of the Capitol Full Stack Software Engineer

Sept 2020 - May 2021 • Washington, DC (remote)

- I came into an existing monolithic app migration from .NET 4.x to .NET Core 3.x and had to adapt to a new team unfamiliar with the app, where I became the "pointman". Since I worked on the app previously, I was the one with all the historical knowledge and context and provided insight to the team on data relationships, why decisions were made around code architecture, and to clarify expected application use cases.
- I optimized and improved the code quality by owning the rewriting of the client application from an MVC view-based approach to a SPA and upgraded to React 16.5, rewriting all class-based components to functional components with hooks, implemented the Context API for global storage and authored over 330 individual tests across 110 test suites to react 80% code coverage. Since I wrote the client app 2 years prior, it gave me the opportunity to catch all my oversights and apply newfound knowledge.
- I helped speed up future schema migrations by writing many different SQL scripts to be used for every 2-year cycle.
- I had a direct impact on the onboarding process for new hires and developers across the broader organization new to the codebase by authoring all documentation and defined best practices and principles to follow for the front end architecture.
- Limpacted the efficiency of stakeholder feature demos and QA testing by creating SQL scripts to mimic specific application states, which were used by both developers and QA for testing bugs and setting up feature demos, resulting in a more seamless workflow and a happier client during demos.
- Tech Used: NET, C#, SQL, React, Jest, SignalR, Hangfire, React Testing Library, Sass, Bootstrap, ESLint, Prettier, Team Foundation Server

Gloo, LLC Senior Software Engineer - Web

June 2019 - Sept 2020 . Boulder, CO

- I worked on the Accounts/Registration team for onboarding new users and organizations registering with the Gloo platform. We
 solved the problem for tracking where a new user's external origin was, and through logic, determining their proper destination to
 be, scaling for an SSO model across the platform's host of products. Our UIs had a direct impact on every user, optimizing the conversion rates for successful registrations through efficient user flows, registrations, password resets, verification codes via email, etc.
- As the only full-time employee web engineer on our team, I was responsible for ensuring our Gloo Web team policies and practices
 were being upheld through code reviews, guidance, and patience.
- I contributed to the internal Gloo Web team by authoring two NPM packages to implement custom Google Analytics and Facebook tags within our Next.js applications.
- I sped up our onboarding process for web contributors by spearheading a Naming Conventions Best Practices doc on front end code
 for React, Apollo GraphQL, Rosie, Jest, Next.js, etc. authoring it, coordinating with team members for input, and getting everyone to
 sign off on it, which we later adopted and included our onboarding docs for new hires or contractors.
- Tech Used: Microservices, Next.js, Apollo GraphQL, Express, CircleCl, Heroku, Docker, Kubernetes, Jest, Cypress, React Testing Library, Emotion, Material UI. Formik, Rollbar

Architect of the Capitol Full Stack Software Engineer

Mar 2018 - June 2019 • Washington, DC (remote)

Project - Compass

- I led the front end development during a redesign of the internal SharePoint intranet for employees about organizational news, events, and other important information.
- I optimized and reduced the time and stress for content creators within the organization by planning, developing, and launching an internal tool for creating custom SharePoint content, catered to the site. This was used by internal employees that were responsible for creating events, promotionals, articles, image uploads, etc within Compass.
- $\bullet \quad \text{I helped mentor other team members on pieces of code / development concepts when the time was needed.} \\$

Project - Senate Suites

- I owned the client application development during an enterprise app redesign in .NET, migrating from an MVC architecture with views written in Razor to views written in React. I leveraged Redux for state management and Webpack for modular bundle sizes, ensuring only proper bundles were loaded for relative pages within the app.
- I ushered in and implemented a testing strategy in Jest and Enzyme, resulting in a test coverage of 78% of all client code. Previously, there were no tests implemented at all.
- I also supported migrating features from ColdFusion into .NET, and implemented WebAPIs for a RESTful approach, resulting in a faster and less buggy app.
- I worked directly with stakeholders of the project, organizing and planning feature work, tech debt, and long term trajectory, while building up client communication skills.
- * Tech Used: C#, .NET, SQL, React, TypeScript, Redux, Jest, Enzyme, jQuery, SharePoint, CAML, Webpack, ESLint, Less

Evolver, Inc. Front End Software Engineer

Apr 2017 - Mar 2018 • Centennial, CO

- I dramatically improved the user experience for over 10,000 users by optimizing client code and refactoring a .NET MVC web app with jQuery to using React and Redux.
- I brought in shipping confidence for the app and improved our deployment pipeline by implementing a testing harness in Jest and Enzyme covering over 75% of client code, configuring linting with ESLint and formatting with Prettier for overall code quality.
- * Tech Used: C#, .NET, React, ES6 JavaScript, CSS, Sass, Webpack, Redux, Jest, Enzyme, Prettier, Jira, jQuery

Crawford & O'Brien Lead Web Developer

Sep 2015 - Apr 2017 • Tempe, AZ (remote)

- I served as the lead developer for a digital marketing agency performing any and all tech related tasks for over 40 clients, including but not limited to: development of Wordpress and Shopify sites with custom themes, continued client support requests, DNS and content migrations, emails, security, backups, site speed optimizations, SEO, etc.
- I built up personal communication skills by working directly with the clients to find out their needs and accomplishing the tasks needed to meet those. I was the main point of contact for direct requests for their websites, and I interacted with them on a 1:1 basis.
- As our department lead, I directed and managed 3 junior developers by delegating tasks and implementing, documenting and overseeing our processes of web development.
- Tech Used: WordPress, PHP, Shopify, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Google Analytics, WooCommerce, Yoast SEO, Trello

Access-Now Web Developer/Designer

Dec 2014 - Jan 2015 • Denver, CO

- As a contributor, I designed and built dynamic, responsive websites and custom logos and marketing materials for a digital marketing agency. I worked directly with clients.
- Tech Used: WordPress, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, cPanel, Plesk, Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator

SKILLS

Programming Languages

C#, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, GraphQL, HTML, CSS,

Frameworks & Tooling

.NET, Node, Express, Nest.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Apollo React, Vue, Next.js, Nuxt.js, Redux, React Native Jest, React Testing Library, Enzyme, Cypress Amazon Web Services, Git, CircleCl, Heroku, Webpack,

Other

Communication, project planning, team collaboration self-management, emotional intelligence, mentorship

Certifications

Certified ScrumMaster ScrumAlliance Certificate ID #355624

EDUCATION

SeedPaths

Aug 2014 - Oct 2014 • Denver, CO 8-week intensive software development bootcamp learning full stack, object-oriented programming in C#, .NET, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SQL, Git

Louisiana State University

Aug 2008 - May 2011 • Baton Rouge, LA Landscape Architecture & Communication Studies

ENTREPRENEURIAL

Althea Web Services, LLC

June 2016 – Present • Denver, CO I'm the sole-proprietor of a business where I provide web development services via freelancing or contractual agreements. I also operate under this

name as a means to publish personal projects and secure my own intellectual property.